CAREER PROFILE

I have been a developer for more than 20 years, with the last 8 using PHP and specialising in web technologies. in a LAMP/LEMP environment. I have used ZF1 and most recently Laravel and Lumen, which are my preferred choices. I have built product from scratch as well as maintained and enhanced existing ones.

I would like to move towards a more leading position, to take a step-back for development and where I would be able to also mentor more junior developers.

EXPERIENCES

Lead Backend Developer

April 2017 - Present

London Review of Books, London

- Setting up development sites on AWS
- · Supporting the frontend developers
- Building API to retrieve content and support an SPA
- Working on rewriting the website using Laravel 5.5, gathering requirements, writing tests and code, preparing for demos, etc.

Backend Developer

January 2017 - March 2017

Your Favourite Story

• Built internal web-based tool to upload files to client server, using Lumen 5.2

Web Developer

January 2016 - December 2016

City A.M., London

- Build a new API server in Lumen 5.2
- Worked on upgrading two sites from Laravel 4.2 to 5.2
- Worked on rebranding of old site
- · Continued working on existing in-house CMS for new features and bug-fixing
- Daily use of GIT for branching and merging

PHP Developer

January 2011 - October 2016

Mediatel, London

- Mentored a Junior developer on Mediatel products, our coding standards, Zend Framework and general OOPHP
- Contributed to the development of a mapping feature in our core product using PostGIS, TinyOWS, Mapnik and React.
- Developed new website, front (JavaScript and jQuery) and back-end (PHP, MySQL and ZF1), for company's events, with booking and payment facilities (PayPal API), and provided support and training on how to use it (from an admin point of view)
- Designed, coded (PHP, MySQL and ZF1) and implemented a process to load survey data from different providers, using XML to defined what to import.

Technical Consultant

August 2006 - December 2010

Linedata Services (UK) Ltd, London

- Developed a framework of Perl scripts and classes to help Subversion administrators and users
- · Provided internal and external technical support
- Managed the migration from CMS on OpenVMS to Subversion on Linux

Analyst Programmer

March 2001 - August 2006

Linedata Services (UK) Ltd, London

• Added new functionality and scripts to help developers and tester in using subversion



Giulio Troccoli-Allard

Lead Backend Developer

giulio@troccoli.it

troccoli.it

troccoli

366144/giuliot

in giulio-troccoli

giuliotroccoli

EDUCATION

Certificate of Higher Education in Web Design Technologies Birkbeck 2010

MSc in Computer Science Università degli Studi di Udine (Italy) 1998

LANGUAGES

Italian (Native)

English (Fluent)

Spanish (Intermediate)

Japanese (Beginners)

INTERESTS

Volunteering

Volleyball

Cooking

- Co-managed, designed and developed the Subversion system, a Control Management System, for few of our products
- Improved the development process on Unix platforms with scripts (written in ksh and using awk and sed) for developers
- Developed a new connector to retrieve market data from specific vendors
- Designed a new functionality to import financial data from an external source via XML. The XML document was written against a XML Schema
- Developed for a real time back office investment management, administration, portfolio
 valuation and investment reporting solution. The product is platform-independent, with
 only a small kernel developed for a specific environment

Analyst Programmer

June 1998 - November 2000

S.T. - Sistemi Telematici, Palmanova (Italy)

- Coordinated a group of 5 programmers in a redesigning project. The code was written in C and COBOL, with embedded SQL. All the procedures ran on a Unix machine with Informix
- Developed, upgraded and managed applications to administrate vehicular traffic for a motorway company. The procedures were written in C with embedded SQL, and ran on a AIX machine with IBM Universal Database
- Developed software for a business firm. All coded in COBOL with Embedded SQL. All
 procedures ran on a Unix-like machine in a Task Manager environment (CICS)



Most of my work has been done when working and is therefore copyrighted. Here are the few examples of projects I am working on or have contributed to

London Volleyball Association - An attempt to write a more modern site for the LVA League Admins

iCal - A fork of the original markuspoerschke/iCal repo, to which I contributed.



Last update: 10 October 2017

SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

Designed with ♥ by Xiaoying Riley for developers